#### **ALVI AN NOOR**

Address: 237, Anowara Monjil, Dakhil Madrasa Road, Kawlar Moddho Para,

Dakshinkhan, Dhaka.

Email: alvi284@gmail.com | +88 01720248787



## **OBJECTIVE**

• Want to work in a well reputed organization having the intention to work being honest, sincere and to learn and take responsibilities, face challenge and to gather experience.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

• Epic Group-Cosmopolitan Industries Pvt. Ltd

**Duration**: February 2021-Present **Designation**: Senior Executive **Department**: Utility & Engineering

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for all Utility-Engineering Operation & Maintenance work & Follow up Schedule Maintenance, Preventive Maintenance, Break-Down Maintenance & Shut-Down Maintenance Process.
- Responsible for the Operation, Maintenance & Troubleshooting of Generator Power system. Monitoring REB Sub-Station.
- o Monitoring Operation, Maintenance & Troubleshooting of Boiler including EGB and Rotary Screw type Air Compressor. Steam & Air generation-distribution.
- o Monitoring Full Factory HVAC system-0&M, Trouble shooting for 2000 RT Capacity Chiller M/C, AHU-FCU, Dehumidifier, all Split type, Cassette type A/C.
- o Prepare Requisition of machine & engine spare parts & materials Indent, Documentary Tracking.
- o Working on Dyeing-Washing Plant, W.F. section Leggar-Topper, Washing R&D, Washing Lab, Oven-Vacuum overall Machinery Preventive & Breakdown Maintenance.
- Troubleshooting of full factory all Pump-Motor Mechanical & Electrical related problem. Cargo Lift regular maintenance. Monitoring Mechanical Workshop, Gearbox, Bearing-Belt & all kinds of Welding related work.
- o Co-ordinate with New Project, making BOQ, T&A, TBA for the New Project. GRN Checking for the materials. ACCORD, ALLIANCE, NIRAPON & others audit related work.

## • Italian-Thai Development Public Company Limited (Metro Rail Project)

**Duration:** October 2018-September 2020

**Description:** Worked on **Metro Rail Project** as Project Mechanical Engineer

**Department:** Ground Support Erection

Responsibilities:

Responsible for smooth erection work, maintain hydraulic jack pressure during erection, steel structure fabrication, drawing modification in AutoCAD, fabrication work inspection, welding quality inspection, maintain safe working environment on site, monitoring day to day affairs as team leader, make weekly and monthly project planning correspondence with the project engineers, giving day to day solutions for problems in the project.

## • Hi-Tech Bangla (Bangladesh) Limited

**Duration**: August 2017-September 2018

**Description:** Worked on Hi-Tech Bangla (Bangladesh) Limited as Engineer-I (Mechanical)

**Department:** Engineering Service

**Responsibilities:** 

Engineering design using solidworks, database management, CRM management, budget and report making and as per company task.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Made the first ever hybrid racing car of Bangladesh as a member of "**Team Swapnojan**" and represented the country by participating in the **Student Formula Hybrid Vehicle Challenge** 2017 in India organized by Imperial Society of Innovative Engineers (ISIE). Got prizes in two different categories which is the **Go Green** award and the **Future Vehicle award**.

## **PROIECT**

• Auto Feed Pneumatic Drilling Machine

**Description**: The main objective of our project is to perform machining operation using "Auto Feed Mechanism" in drilling machine with the help of pneumatic sources. Pneumatic cylinders with pistons and solenoid valves were used and connected with the drilling machine to give the forward and reverse feed.

#### **THESIS**

• Heat Conduction of Composite Materials

Advisor: Prof. Dr. M. H. Khan

**Description:** A heat conduction apparatus has been made with copper plates, composite material, a heater and the whole box was insulated with glass wool. Water supply was given to the box through a centrifugal pump from outside. Thermocouples were placed and reading was taken of the upper copper plate, lower copper plate, composite material, and the heater to measure the thermal conductivity of the composite material.

### **EDUCATION**

- Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Dhaka, Bangladesh
  - o B.Sc in Mechanical Engineering Passing Year: 2017
  - o CGPA: 2.96/4.00
- Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh, Bangladesh
  - o Higher Secondary Certificate Exam (H.S.C) Passing Year: 2012
  - o GPA: 5.0/5.0 (Golden)
- Govt. Laboratory High School, Mymensingh, Bangladesh
  - o Secondary School Certificate Exam (S.S.C) Passing Year: 2010
  - o GPA: 5.0/5.0

#### SKILL

- Microsoft Office: Professional working experience in MS Word, MS Excel and PowerPoint.
- Engineering Analytical Tool: AutoCAD, Solidworks, MATLAB, Pspice.
- Utilities: Adobe Photoshop, Internet Literacy, E-mailing.
- **Typing:** Very good typing speed.

# **SEMINAR AND INDUSTRIAL TOUR**

• Visited Runner Automobiles assembly and engineering section in Bhaluka.

- Visited Kaptai Hydro-Electric Power Plant and gathered knowledge on the working principle of Hydro-Electric Power Plant.
- Participated in the seminar on "Supply Chain Management".

## MAJOR SUBJECTS IN ENGINEERING

Thermodynamics \*Machine Design \* Heat Transfer
 Fluid Mechanics \*Power Plant Economy \*Control Engg.
 Automobile Engg. \*Mechatronics \*Applied Math

# TRAINING COURCES

• IELTS

o Institute: British Council Bangladesh.

o Duration: 3 months

o Year: 2018

## LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Bengali: Mother tongue.

English: Very good communication skill in both writing and speaking.

# PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name: A.K.M. Mahbub Alam

**Profession:** Professor (Physics) and Vice Principle (Retd), Govt. Ananda Mohan College,

Mymensingh.

Mother's Name: Anjuman Ara Begum

**Profession:** Associate Professor (Zoology), Govt. Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh.

**Date of Birth:** July 6, 1995 **Hometown:** Mymensingh

Religion: Islam

**Blood Group:** O(+ve)

# REFERENCES

# A.S.M. Monjur Imam

Controller Of Accounts, Biman Bangladesh Airlines.

Address: Room #601, Biman Head Office,

Balaka Bhaban, Dhaka

Email: Controller@bd.biman.com Contact Number: 01777715526

## MD. Jubayer Hossain

Assistant Professor
Department of Mechanical Eng,
Ahsanullah University of
Science and Technology, Dhaka.
+8801911099149

hossain.jubayer@gmail.com

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby, declare that the above furnished information is true to the best of my knowledge.



Signature